<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sidney Soh</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sidney Soh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and the lee.so; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internship at Kidocode</title>
      <link>/post/internship-kidocode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/internship-kidocode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;internship-overview&#34;&gt;Internship Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7th August 2023 - 7th September 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducted Seaborn workshop for more than 12 people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of Review and Test team for newly created coding courses on C#, Python and Data Science for children and teens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teaching Python with Blockly, Electronics and MIT App Inventor to children ages 5 - 13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gained knowledge in basic C# programming, basic JavaScript programming, and several Python libraries (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experiences-at-kidocode&#34;&gt;My Experiences at Kidocode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently interning at Kidocode, a technology and entrepreneurship school dedicated to nurturing young children and teenagers into future leaders. The company was established in 2014, and now has over 6,800 students.
&lt;/br&gt; &lt;/br&gt;
During my internship, I had the opportunity to contribute my skills and passion to the Mathematics and Data Science Department, where I worked as a teacher assistant for a month.
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
One of the highlights of my internship was being an integral part of the Review and Test team for Kidocode&amp;rsquo;s coding courses. I played a role in accelerating the course development process and ensuring the quality of content before its release to students. My involvement encompassed courses spanning diverse programming languages including C#, Python (Turtle), and Data Science. My contributions enriched my understanding of the curriculum development process and provide valuable insights that contributed to the courses&amp;rsquo; readiness for student engagement.
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
Among my achievements, I conducted a Data Science workshop on Seaborn, a Python visualization library, catering to an audience of 12 participants. This experience enhanced my public speaking and presentation skills.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
I dedicated myself to continuous learning and skill development. I delved into the realm of basic JavaScript and C#, Electronics, and learned MIT App Inventor for mobile app development. Additionally, I honed my proficiency in essential Python libraries, including NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn, equipping me with versatile tools for data analysis and visualization.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
Beyond the technical aspects, my internship at Kidocode enriched my soft skills as well. The demands of multitasking between diverse responsibilities such as student instruction, composing student reports, and testing courses enhanced my time management abilities. As I interacted with fellow team members and students, I further developed strong communication skills that were vital in conducting workshops and providing constructive feedback during testing phases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literature Society MCKL</title>
      <link>/post/literature-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/literature-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;founded-the-society-in-may-2022&#34;&gt;Founded the Society in May 2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My growing passion in the world of literature inspired me to found and be the President of the first ever Literature Society in MCKL. The society gained over 50 club members in the span of a year, and we conducted several society meetups where club members would band together and discuss certain works of literature, including movies, books and poems.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As President, my responsibilities included delegating tasks to my fellow committee members, leading discussions during committee meetings, and overseeing all of the society activities. I played an important role in keeping the society active, and then personally recruited new committee members to continue the legacy of the society in years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;society-event&#34;&gt;Society Event&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 11th 2022, Literature Society collaborated with Psychology Society and hosted a Murder Mystery Event for our club members. Our event planning team created the murder mystery storyline, planned and created the props, and designed the riddles and clues for the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;photo-gallery&#34;&gt;Photo Gallery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 2&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 3&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 4&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 5&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 6&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-pic6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 7&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-clue.png&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 8&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/litsociety/event-plans.png&#34; alt=&#34;Event photo 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project RootTech</title>
      <link>/post/project-roottech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/project-roottech/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview A college project involving 8 students, who gathered together and raised funds for underprivileged children to take a digital literacy course by ICDL. These children attended the classes for a month and graduated with globally recognized certificates.
Project Timeline Project RootTech lasted from January 2022 to June 2022. We first begun by brainstorming ideas on how to carry our goals forward, and decided to fund the children of BJCK (Buku Jalanan Chow Kit), a non-profit organization providing underprivileged children with education opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
